Peter Jones

Software Engineer Atlanta, GA | (404) 452-3580

| github.com/codymccoderson | linkedin.com/in/peterjones | peteflux@gmail.com

Creative software engineer with high adaptability to any environment. Prior to being a software engineer, I worked as a paralegal for a boutique law firm and an English teacher overseas in Korea. I'm also a semi-professional hip-hop artist with a love for travel and new experiences.

Software Development Skills

Debugging, JavaScript, Python, Node.js, React, Express, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

Education

The University of Miami | B.A. in Business Administration | Coral Gables, FL August 2004 – May 2008 |
DigitalCrafts | Certificate in Software Engineering | Atlanta, GA January 2020 – May 2020

 Software engineering training program covering full-stack development including, but not limited to JavaScript, Python, including an emphasis on cutting-edge frameworks like React and server-side technologies including Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL

Software Development Portfolio

Solo Dolo | solodolo.netlify.com | github.com/codymccoderson/solodolo

March 2020

- Member of a 3-person development team building a climbing review site that allows users to plot and save their routes up the mountain
- Worked on the every aspect of the site, including the database, routes, models, views, styling, and researching HTML Canvas to plot the user path
- Built with Node.js, Express, PostgresQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, HTML Canvas

Fast Food Revenge | github.com/codymccoderson/fastfoodrevenge

February 2020

- Member of a 3-person development team building a site that calculates the amount of time necessary to burn unwanted calories by your preferred method of exercise.
- Responsibilities included designing and assembling a fully responsive layout and organization of information pulled from the API
- Built with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery

Professional Work Experience

Harris General Counsel Services | Paralegal | Kennesaw, GA

May 2015 – Present

- Created structure and organized entire client database of files using Sharepoint and SmartVault
- Performed 50 state trademark name searches and prepared reports of findings
- Performed ad-hoc research and prepared memos for attorney review

Avalon | English Teacher | Anyang, South Korea

January 2014 – February 2015

- Taught Avalon curriculum as an after-school instructor for students between 4th and 6th grade
- Built many soft skills working in a team with other foreign instructors and reporting to our Korean co-teachers
- Combined an effective use of the whiteboard with interactive games to maximize the learning experience for students

Additional details on prior work experience available upon request